"The Healthiest Food
Sources of Vitamin B12"
A regular, reliable source of vitamin
B12 is critical for anyone eating
a plant-based diet, either
vitamin B12 supplements
or vitamin B12 fortified foods.
I've talked about my B12
supplement recommendations,
either 50 micrograms a day, or once
a week doses of 2,000 micrograms.
I think that's the simplest, cheapest
way: taking it once a week.
That's how I do it. But if you
don't want to take supplements,
you'd have to rely on B12-fortified
foods, in which case you'd have
to eat three separate servings
of B12-fortified foods,
each ideally containing at least
190% of the so-called "Daily Value"
on the product's nutrition facts label.
How does that make any sense?
And what's the term "Daily Value"
even mean? The term Daily Value
is used to designate both the
DRV, Daily Reference Values,
and RDI, Reference Daily
Intakes, that are based on the
Recommended Daily Allowances,
all to limit consumer confusion.
See, aren't you less confused now?
Anyway, the daily value of B12 was
set at 6, which was recently changed
to 2.4 in 2020, making it
all the more confusing,
and so 190% of 2.4
is about 4.5.
Plug that into the equation
I detailed in the last video
and you get about 1.16
absorbed from each serving,
times three times a day, and poof:
there's your 3.5 for the day.
OK, so how much like nutritional
yeast would that be,
a commonly B12-fortified food
source? It depends on the brand.
Going alphabetically, Bob's Red Mill
brand has 730% per quarter cup,
so you'd only need about 4 times
less than that to make up a serving,
so around one tablespoon.
So one tablespoon of this brand
sprinkled on each meal and your
B12 would be taken care of.
Bragg's says it's even more
potent at 563% per tablespoon;
so just a teaspoon three
times a day should suffice.
Dr. Fuhrman's brand is explicitly
unfortified, and so contains zero B12,
so that's an important lesson. You can't
just assume nutritional yeast has B12.
So if you find it in the bulk section;
I mean you have no idea
what it contains unless
you actually see the package.
Same with the Frontier Co-op
brand: zero vitamin B12.
KAL brand has 500% of the Daily Value
of B12 per three rounded tablespoons,
so one rounded tablespoon should
suffice as one of the servings.
NOW brand has more, with
two teaspoons sufficing.
Red Star has 333% per
one-and-a-half heaping tablespoons,
so a serving would be
like one tablespoon,
but note only some of Red Star's
nutritional yeast varieties
have any B12 at all. So just
remember to check the label.
And finally, Trader Joe's looks like 1.5
tablespoons could count as one serving.
So it looks like Bragg's is the
most potent currently available.
There are all sorts of other B12
fortified foods from plant-based
meats and milks to breakfast
cereals and energy drinks,
but are there any other green light
sources, meaning plant foods from
which nothing bad has been added
and nothing good has been taken away?
What about various algae-type
products like spirulina,
which are advertised as
natural vitamin B12 sources?
Not only do they not actually contain
B12 that's useable for humans,
it's even worse than that.
They may contain B12 analogues,
look-alike molecules that can even
block your absorption of real B12.
I was excited to see that there
was an herbal tea with B12,
but so little you'd have
to quadruple bag it.
If you didn't want to take a pill, which
again I think is really the best way,
the easiest option would
probably be LeafSide foods.
I've always loved them because
they center their ingredients
around my Daily Dozen. Unfortunately,
people see them citing my science
and think I have some sort of financial
relationship, but of course I have
no financial ties to any food company,
drug company, supplements, kitchen
gadgets—no personal financial ties with
any commercial entity whatsoever, ever.
I'm happy to voluntarily plug LeafSide
though, as their food has kept me
from starving on the road on many
occasion. They're freeze-dried,
so they're light and easy to travel
with, and I just use my hotel room
coffee maker to make
hot water and poof.
But anyway, each of their meals
has 75 mcg of B12. So one a day
and you'd get all your B12 without
having to take a supplement,
but it's only 100% green light if you
specify you want the salt-free versions.
They have no added salt/fat/sugar
versions of all their products
at no extra cost, but you have
to specify that when you order.
Note you have to throw all these
recommendations out the window
for anyone over age 65 and go straight
to high daily supplement doses,
which I'll cover in my next video,
as well as my recommendations
during pregnancy, breastfeeding,
infancy, and childhood.